import React from "react";
export const gramma = [
  {
    semester: 1,
    grade: 8,
    questions: [
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: `<p><b>Exercise 1: Fill in the correct form of the word in parentheses</b></p>`,
        question: `She enjoys (read) ………. books in her free time. 
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `reading`,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `<p>enjoy + V_ing</p>`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `The question is easy _____ (answer).
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `to answer`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `To Infinitive làm tân ngữ của tính từ.`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `They practiced (sing) ………. together before the performance.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `singing`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `practice + V_ing`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `The man asked me how _____ (get) to the airport.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `to get`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `To Infinitive làm tân ngữ chỉ người`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `The teacher expected Sarah _____ (study) hard.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `to study`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `To Infinitive làm tân ngữ chỉ người`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `I suggest (visit) ………. the museum while you’re in town.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `visiting`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `suggest + V_ing: `,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `I learned _____ (ride) the bike at the age of 5
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `to ride`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `Learn to + V:	Học để làm điều gì đó`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `He admitted (cheat) ………. on the test.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `cheating`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `admitted + V_ing: thừa nhận`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `We’re considering (take) ………. a trip to the mountains next weekend.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `taking`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `consider + V_ing: cân nhắc, xem xét`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: ` It was a nice day, so we decided ________ for a walk. (go)
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `to go`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `Decide to + V:	Quyết định làm gì`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `Have you ever thought about (learn) ………. a new language?
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `learning`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `thought about + V_ing: suy nghĩ về việc gì đó`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `They don’t have much money. They can’t afford __________ out very often. (go)
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `to go`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `Afford to + V: 	Chi trả cho việc gì`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `She avoids (eat) ………. junk food for better health.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `eating`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `avoid + V_ing: tránh làm gì đó`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `They discussed (start) ………. a new business venture.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `starting`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `discussed + V_ing: thảo luận về việc gì đó`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `Our neighbour threatened __________ the police if we didn’t stop the noise. (call)
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `to call`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `threatened to + V: đe dọa làm gì đó`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `Are you interested in (join) ………. the club?
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `joining`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `interested in + V_ing: quan tâm đến việc gì đó, V_ing theo sao giới từ`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `Hurry up! I don’t want to risk ____________ the rain. (miss)
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `missing`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `risk + V_ing: mạo hiểm làm gì đó`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `He apologized for (arrive) ………. late to the meeting.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `arriving`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `apologized for + V_ing: xin lỗi về việc gì đó, V_ing theo sao giới từ`,
      },
     
    ],
  },
  {
    semester: 1,
    grade: 8,
    questions: [
      
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: `<p><b>Exercise 2: Choose the correct answer</b></p>`,
        question: `The children enjoy ………. stories before bedtime.
            `,
        options: [`reading`, `to read`, `read`, `reads`],
        answer: `1`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `enjoy + V_ing: thích làm gì đó`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `She avoids ………. out late at night alone.
            `,
        options: [ `go`,`going`, `to go`, `goes`],
        answer: `2`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `avoid + V_ing: tránh làm gì đó`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `We discussed the possibility of ………. a trip to Europe next summer.
            `,
        options: [`take`, `taking`, `to take`, `takes`],
        answer: `2`,       
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `Gerund theo sau giới từ`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `I dream about ______ a big house.
            `,
        options: [`To build`, `build`, `building`],
        answer: `3`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `sau giới từ about là V_ing`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `She doesn't mind ________ the night shift.
            `,
        options: [`Working`, `to work`, `work`],
        answer: `1`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `mind + V_ing: không phiền làm gì đó`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `The man asked me how ______ to the airport.
            `,
        options: [`To get`, `getting`, `get`],
        answer: `1`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `ask + somebody + to V: hỏi ai đó làm gì`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `He agreed _______ a new car.
            `,
        options: [`To buy`,`Buying`,`buy`],
        answer: `1`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `agree + to V`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `I look forward to ______ you at the weekend.
            `,
        options: [`See`,`Seeing`,`to see`],
        answer: `2`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `sau giới từ to`,
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    semester:1,
    grade:8,
    questions:[      
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: `<p><b>Rewrite the sentences</b></p>`,
        question: `I like making crafts especially bracelet.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `making crafts especially bracelet`,
        rewrite: `I enjoy`,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `enjoy + V_ing`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `Minh doesn't like making models because it is very boring.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `making models because it is very boring`,
        rewrite: `Minh detests`,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `detest + V_ing: get làm gì`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `My brother likes making pottery because it is a creative activity.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `on making pottery because it is a creative activity`,
        rewrite: `My brother is hooked`,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `hooked on + V_ing: very interested in / addicted to / really enjoys: rất thích`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `We enjoy doing gardening because it is very relaxing.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `on doing gardening because it is very relaxing`,
        rewrite: `We are keen`,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `"keen on" = interested in / enthusiastic about / enjoy + V_ing`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `Shall we go for a walk?
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `going for a walk`,
        rewrite: `What about`,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `What about + V_ing`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `Why don’t we visit our teacher?
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `visiting our teacher`,
        rewrite: `I suggest `,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `suggest + V_ing`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: ` I am very pleased that we shall meet again soon
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `forward to our meeting again soon.`,
        rewrite: `I’m looking`,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `Look forward to+ V_ing: mong chờ, háo hức về điều gì, việc gì đó`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `It is really quite easy to learn English
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `really quite easy.`,
        rewrite: `Learning English is `,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `Ving đứng đầu câu đóng vai trò chủ ngữ<br/>Learning English is + O`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `Complaining about the matter is useless now.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `useless to complain about the matter.`,
        rewrite: `It is`,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: ` It+ be+ adj+ to V: thật... để làm gì (useless)`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `I don’t want to go to the movie tonight
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `going to the movie theater tonight.`,
        rewrite: `I don’t feel like`,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `like + V_ing`,
      },
    ]
  },  
  {
    semester: 1,
    grade: 8,
    questions: [
      
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: `<p><b>Gerund or Infinitive – Fill in the correct form.</b></p>`,
        question: `They are likely __________________ up at any time. (show)
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `to show`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `sau tính từ likely + to V`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `The man denied __________ the crime. (commit)
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `committing`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `deny + V_ing`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `Their memories of ____________ in Africa will stay with them forever. (travel)
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `traveling`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `sau giới từ of + V_ing`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `He has always been afraid of ____________. (fly)
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `flying`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `sau giới từ of + V_ing`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `____________ is good for your health. (swim)
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `Swimming`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `Gerund Thường được sử dụng khi hành động là có thật<br/>Gerund làm chủ ngữ trong câu`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `She promised _______________ the report as soon as possible. (read)
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `to read`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `Promise to:	Hứa hẹn làm gì`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `I had a hard time ____________ the situation to my husband. (explain)
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `explaining`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `Cấu trúc: having a hard time: để nói cho ai đó biết rằng bạn đang gặp khó khăn để làm một việc gì đó<br>have difficulty / trouble / a hard time / problems + verb-ing`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `She had some problems ____________ without glasses. (read)
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `reading`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `have difficulty / trouble / a hard time / problems + verb-ing`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `Paul gave up _____________ five years ago. (smoke)
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `smoking`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `sau giới từ +V_ing`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `Most teachers insist on their pupils ______________ (do) the homework.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `doing`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `insist on + noun / pronoun + verb-ing`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `She has often made me ______________ (cry).
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `cry`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `"make" + object + base verb (bare infinitive — without “to”)<br>After verbs like make, let, and help, when followed by an object, we usually use the base form of the verb (not to + verb or verb-ing).`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: ` I expect ____________ (hear) from you by Monday.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `to hear`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `Expect sb to:	Kì vọng ai làm gì`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `I can't make a decision. I keep ______________ (change) my mind.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `changing`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `Keep+ V_ing:	giữ`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `He had made his decision and refused ___________ (change) his mind.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `to change`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `Refuse + to Verb: từ chối cái gì`,
      },
      
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `When I finish (prepare) ________the food, I'll set the table.
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `preparing`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `finish + V_ing: kết thúc làm gì`,
      },
      {
        id: 41,
        extra: ``,
        question: `Do you know how (fix) ________ the screen?
            `,
        options: [],
        answer: `to fix`,
        rewrite: ``,
        lastwrite: ``,
        explanation: `know how + to + verb: biết làm gì`,
      },
    ],
  },
];
